Guide to the J. Claude Evans Family Papers, 1930-2002 RL.10008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Maxilla Evans Materials, 1970s-1990s, 3 boxes
  - Texas Ornithological Society meetings, 1970-1976, 1991, 7 folders (Box 50)
  - Birding notebook, 1979-1980 (Box 50)
  - Breeding records, 1981 (Box 50)
  - Bird records, 1981 (Box 50)
  - Winning canary, 1983 and 1989 (Box 50)
  - Bird notes: Eagles Nest, Utah, Lake Junaluska (Box 50)
  - Bird programs (Box 50)
  - Bird study (Box 50)
  - Bird report (Box 50)
  - Breeding bird survey, 1989 (Box 50)
  - Bird survey, 1977 (Box 50)
  - Smoky Mountain Cage Bird Society directory (Box 50)
  - NCWPS Roanoke R. Spring Meetings, Hills Ferry, 1981-1996, 5 folders (Box 50)
  - NC Nature Conservancy: Halifax County (Box 50)
  - Three Days on the Roanoke (Box 50)
  - Roanoke River Preservation (Box 50)
  - Roanoke River Wildflower trip, 1989 (Box 50)
  - Ivory-Bill (Box 50)
  - Alder Flycatcher (Box 50)
  - Saw Whet Owl, 1979 (Box 50)
  - Band-tailed pigeon (Box 50)
  - Eagle's Nest bird notes (Box 50)
  - Simpson, Mark (Box 51)
  - Bird records (including notebooks), 4 folders (Box 51)
  - Record cards and handbook (Box 51)
  - Bird and flower records (Box 51)
  - 50th Wedding Anniversary, 1990 (Box 51)
  - Eagle's Nest materials, 2 folders (Box 51)
  - Birth certificate, passport (Box 51)
  - Writings (Box 51)
    - "Following the Gray Whale," 1973 (Box 51)
    - "A Beginner Birder," 1992 (Box 51)
    - "Shortia galacifolia," 1999 (Box 51)
  - Correspondence, 1970s-2000s (Box 51)
  - Family correspondence, 1960s and undated (Box 52)
  - Activities
    - Voluntary Simplicity (Box 52)
    - Holy Ground (Box 52)
    - Quaker research (Box 52)
    - Re-Imagining (Box 52)
    - Book reviews (Box 52)
    - Westar Institute (Box 52)
    - FGC Bookstore catalog (Box 52)
    - Quaker and Feminist Christianity publications (Box 52)
- Courses and Notes, 1960s-1990s, 4 boxes
  J. Claude Evans taught and attended many seminars, classes, and workshops in the course of his career as a pastor and counselor. This series includes syllabi, handwritten lecture notes, doodles, pamphlets, and reading materials from an assortment of these events, which have been loosely sorted into Courses Taken, Courses Taught, and General Notes. Many of the courses related to hypnotism, marriage counseling, and spiritual guidance. Courses have been arranged alphabetically by title and date from the 1960s through the 1990s. Many of the notes are on legal-size yellow notebook pages.
  - Courses Taken
    - A-M (Box 53)
    - M-Z (Box 54)
  - Courses Taught
    - A-M (Box 54)
    - M-Z (Box 55)
  - Notes (Box 55)
  - Notes (Box 56)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1975-2000
  - "Women in the Church"; Rev. Carolyn Stapleton; W. Chaplain Evans, Dr. Louise Branscomb, and others; Serial No. 7503, 1975 July 16; 1
    - Original audiocassette, 1975 July 16 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0001)
  - Abortion 1979: Dilemas and Dimensions; The Beginnings of Personhood Part 2; J.C. Evans, Chaplain SMU, 2
    - Original audiocassette, 1979 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0005)
  - J. Claude Evans Dinner; C-90; Bob Cooper, M.C.; 8/20/79, 1979 August 20; 3
    - Original audiocassette, 1979 August 20 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0002)
  - Service of Worship, University Chapel - Southern Meth. Univ., August 26, 1979; Preacher: Chaplain J. Claude Evans; Presiding - Dr. H. Grady Hardin; Soloist - Dr. Lloyd Pfautsch; Scripture: Dr. James Zumberge, President, S.M.U.; Remarks at End: Dr. Zumberge; Organist: Dr. Robert T. Anderson, 1979 August 26; 4
    - Original audiocassette, 1979 August 26 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0003)
  - Service of Worship, University Chapel at S.M.U., August 26, 1979; Preacher: Chaplain J. Claude Evans; Presiding: Dr. H. Grady Hardin; Soloist: Dr. Lloyd Pfautsch; Scripture: Dr. James Zumberge - President SMU; Remarks at End - Dr. Zumberge; Organist: Dr. Robert Anderson, 1979 August 26; 5
    - Original audiocassette, 1979 August 26 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0004)
  - Dr. Claude Evans; "New Look at Marriage and Divorce"; LLUMC Single Young Adult Class; January 13, 1980; 1-1/2 sides, 1980 January 13; 6
    - Original audiocassette, 1980 January 13 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0006)
  - Claude and Max; Washington Street United Methodist Church; A Service of Reconciliation; Peace with Justice Sunday - July 21, 1996; Dr. Claude Evans, Guest Preacher, 1996 July 21; 7
    - Original audiocassette, 1996 July 21 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0007)
  - Southeast Region Annual AAPC Conference; Kanuga, North Carolina - October 25-27, 1996; Chaplain's Devotional; Dr. Claude Evans; Copyright 1996 by SE AAPC, 1996 October 25-27; 8
    - Original audiocassette, 1996 October 25-27 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0008)
  - Southeast Region AAPC Annual Conference; Kanuga Conference Center, NC - October 24-26, 1997; Chaplain's Devotionals; Dr. Claude Evans; Copyright 1997, 1997 October 24-26; 9
    - Original audiocassette, 1997 October 24-26 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0009)
  - Southeast Region AAPC Annual Conference; Kanuga Conference Center, NC - October 23-25, 1998; Chaplain's Devotionals Compilation; Claude J. Evans, ThM; Copyright 1998, 1998 October 23-25; 10
    - Original audiocassette, 1998 October 23-25 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0010)
  - Kanuga-1999-NCAPC; 1. Intro of Maxilla; "10 Minute Stories": 2. Dementia, 3. Dementia, 4. Dementia; J. Claude Evans, Sr., Speaker, 11
    - Original audiocassette, 1999 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0011)
  - Kanuga-1999-NCAPC; 1. Intro of Maxilla; "10 Minute Stories": 2. Dementia, 3. Dementia, 4. Dementia; J. Claude Evans, Sr., Speaker, 12
    - Original audiocassette, 1999 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0012)
  - Kanuga-1999-NCAPC; 1. Intro of Maxilla; "10 Minute Stories": 2. Dementia, 3. Dementia, 4. Dementia; J. Claude Evans, Sr., Speaker, 13
    - Original audiocassette, 1999 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0013)
  - Southeast Region AAPC Annual Conference, Kanuga Conference Center, NC - October 22-24, 1999; Claude Evans; Tape CE 1; Copyright 1999, 1999 October 22-24; 14
    - Original audiocassette, 1999 October 22-24 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0014)
  - Southeast Region AAPC Annual Conference, Kanuga Conference Center, NC - October 22-24, 1999; Claude Evans; Tape CE 2; Copyright 1999, 1999 October 22-24; 15
    - Original audiocassette, 1999 October 22-24 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0015)
  - Southeast Region AAPC Annual Conference, Kanuga Conference Center, NC - October 22-24, 1999; Claude Evans; Tape CE 3; Copyright 1999, 1999 October 22-24; 16
    - Original audiocassette, 1999 October 22-24 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0016)
  - Southeast Region AAPC Annual Conference, Kanuga Conference Center, NC - October 22-24, 1999; Claude Evans; Tape CE 4; Copyright 1999, 1999 October 22-24; 17
    - Original audiocassette, 1999 October 22-24 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0017)
  - Southeast Region AAPC Annual Conference; Kanuga Conference Center, NC - October 22-24, 1999; Chaplain's Devotionals, Claude J. Evans, ThM; Tape CE; Copyright 1999, 1999 October 22-24; 18
    - Original audiocassette, 1999 October 22-24 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0018)
  - Southeast Region AAPC Annual Conference, Kanuga Conference Center, NC - October 27-29, 2000; Devotionals and Stories - 1995; Dr. Claude Evans, Chaplain; Tape CE6A; Copyright 2000, 2000 October 27-29; 19
    - Original audiocassette, 2000 October 27-29 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0019)
  - Southeast Region AAPC Annual Conference, Kanuga Conference Center, NC - October 27-29, 2000; Devotionals and Stories - 1996; Dr. Claude Evans, Chaplain; Tape CE6B; Copyright 2000, 2000 October 27-29; 20
    - Original audiocassette, 2000 October 27-29 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0020)
  - Southeast Region AAPC Annual Conference, Kanuga Conference Center, NC - October 27-29, 2000; Devotionals and Stories - 1997; Dr. Claude Evans, Chaplain; Tape CE6C; Copyright 2000, 2000 October 27-29; 21
    - Original audiocassette, 2000 October 27-29 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0021)
  - Southeast Region AAPC Annual Conference, Kanuga Conference Center, NC - October 27-29, 2000; Devotionals and Stories - 1998; Dr. Claude Evans, Chaplain; Tape CE6D; Copyright 2000, 2000 October 27-29; 22
    - Original audiocassette, 2000 October 27-29 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0022)
      Includes day books, account books, memo books, and rental books.
  - Southeast Region AAPC Annual Conference, Kanuga Conference Center, NC - October 27-29, 2000; Devotionals and Stories - 1999; Dr. Claude Evans, Chaplain; Tape CE6E; Copyright 2000, 2000 October 27-29; 23
    - Original audiocassette, 2000 October 27-29 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0023)
  - Southeast Region AAPC Annual Conference, Kanuga Conference Center, NC - October 27-29, 2000; Devotionals and Stories - 2000; Dr. Claude Evans, Chaplain; Tape CE6F; Copyright 2000, 2000 October 27-29; 24
    - Original audiocassette, 2000 October 27-29 (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0024)
  - First United Methodist Church, 1928 Ross Avenue, Dallas, Texas 75201-3282, (214) 220-2727, FAX (214) 871-9159, Dr. Hal Brady, Pastor; GRIMES MEMORIAL SERVICE, Undated; 25
    - Original audiocassette, Undated (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0025)
  - Psychology and Religion: Friend or Foe; by Dr. Claude Evans; Session 4, Tape 1, Undated; 26
    - Original audiocassette, Undated (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-CS-0026)
  - Foxfire Whipping Scene, Undated; 27
    - Original microcassette, Undated (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-MCS-0001)
  - Foxfire II, [Fast], Undated; 28
    - Original microcassette, Undated (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-MCS-0002)
  - Foxfire 3, Undated; 29
    - Original microcassette, Undated (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-MCS-0003)
  - Foxfire Cues, Undated; 30
    - Original microcassette, Undated (Box 48, Audio-cassette RL10008-MCS-0004)